Guide to the Hill Family Papers, 1662-1994 (bulk 1835-1970)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Hill Family Papers
1662-1994
1835-1970
Hill Family
41 cubic feet (54 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials relating to the Hill family's personal, professional, and political activities. The bulk of the collection relates most directly to Elsie M. Hill (VC 1906).
Biographical Note
Elsie M. Hill (1883-1970) was an American feminist, activist, and leader in the woman suffrage movement. Born in Norwalk, Connecticut in 1883, Hill was the daughter of Mary Ellen Mosman (1846-1918) and Ebenezer J. Hill (1845-1917), a Republican Congressman. In 1906, she graduated from Vassar College and then took a teaching position at a Washington D.C. high school. It was in Washington that she became active in the suffrage movement and began her life-long friendship with Alice Paul. Hill held leading positions in many organizations, but is most well known for her work with the National Woman's Party. Hill's passion for the cause led her to jail (along with her sisters, Clara and Helena) on more than one occasion. After the passage of the 19th amendment, she remained active in the struggle for women's rights, running for public office and working through a variety of organizations to further the cause. From 1921 to 1956 she was married to Albert Lévitt (1887-1968), a lawyer and politician who served as Judge of the U.S. District Court of the Virgin Islands from 1935 to 1937. The marriage made national news because she kept her maiden name, à la Lucy Stone, which was quite shocking for the era. They had one child, Leslie Hill-Lévitt Latham (VC 1945-4). In 1968, at the age of 84, Hill made headlines again when she boarded Pan American Airlines first flight from New York to Moscow. Hill died in Norwalk, Connecticut, on August 6, 1970.
For more biographical details, see Hill's profile on the American Memory site at the Library of Congress.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains correspondence, minutes, reports, press releases, financial and legal papers, clippings, speeches, government documents, articles, and diaries relating to Elsie M. Hill's personal and political activities. Subjects include the National Woman's Party, suffrage, women's rights, Equal Rights Amendment, civil rights, Connecticut politics, civic affairs, her teaching career, history of Joel Barlow, her hobby of breeding Swiss Toggenberg milk goats, and family and personal affairs. Correspondents include Alice Paul, 1915-1970; Anita Pollitzer, 1921-1969; Albert Lévitt, 1921-1968; her sister Clara M. Hill, 1898-1939; and Cary Fink Baynes, 1903-1939. The collection also includes correspondence of Albert Lévitt, 1921-1965, with Robert W. Clairborne, Alice Paul, Roscoe Pound, Elsie Hill, Clara M. Hill, his daughter Elsie Hill-Lévitt, and others. The collection also includes the papers of Clara Mossman Hill, Ebenezer J. Hill, Mary E. Mosman Hill, Albert Lévitt, and other family members.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
National Woman's Party Pamphlet Collection, Vassar College Archives and Special Collections
National Woman's Party Records, Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Interview with Elsie Hill, Center for Oral History Interviews Collection, Archives and Special Collections, University of Connecticut Library
Elsie Hill Interview, Herb Janick Papers, MS012. Western Connecticut State University Archives
Subject Headings
Names:
Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812; Baynes, Cary F.; Clairborne, Robert W.; Hill, Clara M.; Hill, Ebenezer J., 1845-1917; Hill-Lévitt, Elsie; Lévitt, Albert, b. 1887; Paul, Alice, 1885-1977; Pollitzer, Anita, 1894-1975; Pound, Roscoe, 1870-1964
Organizations:
National Woman's Party; United States. Congress. House
Subjects:
Civil rights--United States; Equal rights amendments--United States; Feminism--United States; Feminists--United States; Suffragists--United States; Women--Diaries; Women--Political activity--United States; Women--Social conditions--United States; Women--Suffrage--United States; Women teachers--United States; Women's rights--United States
Places:
Connecticut--Politics and government; United States--Politics and government--20th century; United States--Social life and customs
Document Types:
Audiovisual materials; Clippings (information artifacts); Contracts; Correspondence; Diaries; Financial records; Genealogies (histories); Legal documents; Newsletters; Newspapers; Pamphlets; Photographs; Printed ephemera; Realia; Scrapbooks
VCL Categories
Family; Politics; Women's History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, February 2007.
Additional encoding by Laura Streett, August 2014.
Updated by Emma Gronbeck, November 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Leslie Hill-Levitt Latham in several accessions.
Series List
- Series I. Elsie M. Hill, 1875-1994; (Boxes 1-18)
  - Subseries A. Correspondence
  - Subseries B. Subject Files
  - Subseries C. Clippings
  - Subseries D. Manuscripts and Notes
  - Subseries E. Diaries, Calendars, Address Books and Telephone Lists
  - Subseries F. Financial And Legal
- Series II. Albert Lévitt, 1906-1968; (Boxes 19-26, 41)
  - Subseries A. Correspondence
  - Subseries B. Biographical
  - Subseries C. Financial and Legal
  - Subseries D. Clippings
  - Subseries E. Printed Material
  - Subseries F. Subject Files
  - Subseries G. Writings
- Series III. Clara M. Hill, 1836-1967; (Boxes 26-30, 37-38, 49)
  - Subseries A. Biographical
  - Subseries B. Correspondence
  - Subseries C. Ephemera
  - Subseries D. Financial and Legal
  - Subseries E. Manuscripts
  - Subseries F. Clippings
  - Subseries G. Printed Material
  - Subseries H. Subject Files
- Series IV. Ebenezer Hill, 1800-1919; (Boxes 30-34, 42-49)
  - Subseries A. Correspondence
  - Subseries B. Biographical and Travel
  - Subseries C. Printed Material
  - Subseries D. Writings
- Series V. Mary Mosman Hill, 1835-1952; (Boxes 31, 34-35, 39)
  - Subseries A. Correspondence
  - Subseries B. Biographical
  - Subseries C. Subject Files
  - Subseries D. Writings
- Series VI. Leslie Hill-Lévitt Latham, 1927-1971; (Box 35)
  - Subseries A. Biographical
  - Subseries B. Correspondence
  - Subseries C. Subject Files
  - Subseries D. Printed Material
  - Subseries E. Writings
- Series VII. Mixed Family Materials, (Boxes 31, 35-36, 50-54 )
  - Subseries A. Photographs
  - Subseries B. Miscellaneous
    Miscellaneous letters, documents, recordings and ephemera.
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous Materials, 1662-circa 1923; (Boxes 31, 35, 40, 54)
  This series contains assorted materials from various or unidentified members of the Hill family, including postcards, road maps, and other historical documents and heirlooms.
Container List
- Series I. Elsie M. Hill, 1875-1994
  - Subseries A. Correspondence
    - General Correspondence to Elsie Hill
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1910-1921; (136 letters) (Box 1, Folders 1-13)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1922-1928; (153 letters) (Box 1, Folders 14-23)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1929-1930; (143 letters) (Box 1, Folders 24-35)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1931-1933; (153 letters) (Box 1, Folders 36-49)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1934-1938; (177 letters) (Box 1, Folders 50-63)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1939-1946; (97 letters) (Box 1, Folders 64-73)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1947-1953; (134 letters) (Box 1, Folders 74-85)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1954-1963; (126 letters) (Box 1, Folders 86-97)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1964-1965; (117 letters) (Box 1, Folders 98-106)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1966-1968; (87 letters) (Box 2, Folders 107-115)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, 1969-1970, undated; (64 letters) (Box 2, Folders 116-119)
      - General (chronological) correspondence, fragments, 1918-1949, undated; (9 fragments) (Box 2, Folder 120)
      - General (chronological) correspondence (deteriorated), 1914-1963, undated (Box 17, Folders 1066-1072)
      - Letters from Alice Paul, 1915-1925; (83 letters) (Box 2, Folders 121-131)
      - Letters from Alice Paul, 1926-1951; (99 letters) (Box 2, Folders 132-146)
      - Letters from Alice Paul, 1954-1970; (83 letters) (Box 2, Folders 147-153)
      - Letters from Alice Paul (deteriorated), 1916-1941 (Box 17, Folders 1073-1079)
      - Cards from Alice Paul, undated; (4 cards) (Box 2, Folder 154)
      - Alice Paul to Beatrice Rosenthal, [1962?]; (1 letter) (Box 2, Folder 154A)
      - Letters from Anita Pollitzer, 1921-1960; (77 letters) (Box 2, Folders 155-165)
      - Letters from Anita Pollitzer, 1961-1969, undated; (53 letters) (Box 2, Folders 166-170)
      - Letters from Anita Pollitzer (deteriorated), 1932-1938, undated (Box 17, Folder 1080)
      - Letters from Elie Edson, 1946-1960, undated; (6 letters) (Box 2, Folder 171)
      - Civic Affairs Correspondence, 1909-1962; (53 letters) (Box 2, Folders 172-182)
      - Civic Affairs Correspondence, 1963-1970; (102 letters) (Box 2, Folders 183-192)
      - Civic Affairs Correspondence (deteriorated, from folders 175-178), 1909-1962 (Box 17, Folder 1084)
    - Family Correspondence to Elsie Hill
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1921-1926; (123 letters) (Box 2, Folders 193-203)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1927; (55 letters) (Box 2, Folders 204-210)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folders 211-213)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1929-1933 (Box 3, Folders 214-218)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1934-1935; (74 letters) (Box 3, Folders 219-226)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1935 Jul - 1936 Jun; (82 letters) (Box 3, Folders 227-234)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1936-1938; (59 letters) (Box 3, Folders 235-242)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1939-1940; (72 letters) (Box 3, Folders 243-251)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1940 Apr - 1941 Jun; (79 letters) (Box 3, Folders 252-259)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1941 Aug - 1942 May; (79 letters) (Box 3, Folders 260-269)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1942-1943; (80 letters) (Box 3, Folders 270-278)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1944-1946; (97 letters) (Box 3, Folders 279-289)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1946 Nov - 1955 Jul; (87 letters) (Box 3, Folders 290-300)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt, 1955-1968, undated; (76 letters) (Box 4, Folders 301-308)
      - Letters from Albert Levitt (deteriorated, from folders 228, 259, 267-268), 1935-1942 (Box 17, Folder 1083)
      - Letters from Clara M. Hill, 1898-1952; (212 letters) (Box 4, Folders 309-320)
      - Letters from Clara M. Hill (deteriorated, from folder 318), undated (Box 17, Folder 1085)
      - Letters from family B-L, 1906-1958, undated; (112 letters) (Box 4, Folders 321-332)
      - Letters from family M-W, 1905-1968; (52 letters) (Box 4, Folders 333-340)
      - Letters from family W-Y, 1937-1968; (85 letters) (Box 4, Folders 341-346)
      - Miscellaneous family letters, 1913-1966; (12 letters) (Box 4, Folder 347)
    - Personal Correspondence to Elsie Hill
      - General, arranged chronologically, 1901-1970, undated; (353 letters) (Box 4, Folders 348-377)
      - General (deteriorated), 1928-1968, undated (Box 17, Folder 1081)
      - From Cary Fink (VC 1906), 1903-1909; (39 letters) (Box 5, Folders 378-385)
      - From Cary Fink (VC 1906), 1910-1939; (42 letters) (Box 5, Folders 386-392)
      - From Violet Pike Penty (VC 1907), 1905-1929; (8 letters) (Box 5, Folder 393)
      - Re: goat breeding, 1923-1936, undated; (96 letters) (Box 5, Folders 394-401)
      - Re: Joel Barlow, 1934-1968; (79 letters) (Box 5, Folders 402-409)
      - Re: Joel Barlow, 1940-1941, undated (Box 17, Folder 1082)
      - Re: Hill's teaching career, 1911-1943; (17 letters) (Box 5, Folders 410-411)
      - Greeting Cards, undated (Box 5, Folders 412-417)
    - Correspondence from Elsie Hill to Others
      - Letters to Frederick A. Hill [brother], 1901; (2 letters) (Box 5, Folder 418)
      - Letters to Helena Hill Weed [sister], 1901; (3 letters) (Box 5, Folder 419)
      - Miscellaneous, 1901- circa 1969, undated; (117 letters) (Box 5, Folders 420-431)
  - Subseries B. Subject Files - Social and Political Activism
    - National Woman's Party
      - National Council Meeting Minutes, 1921-1946 (Box 6, Folders 432-445)
      - National Council Meeting Minutes (deteriorated, from folders 434-444), 1930-1938 (Box 18, Folders 1087-1089)
      - National Council Meeting Agenda, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 446)
      - Membership Reports, 1921-1923 (Box 6, Folder 447)
      - Committee Reports, 1924-1969 (Box 6, Folder 448)
    - Legal Materials
      - Work done by Legal Research Dept., 1922 (Box 6, Folder 449)
      - Miscellaneous legal documents, 1951-1962 (Box 6, Folder 450)
      - Proposed by-laws, undated (Box 6, Folder 451)
      - By-laws, 1938-1949, undated (Box 6, Folder 452)
      - Inez Milholland Memorial Committee, undated (Box 6, Folder 453)
      - State and federal legislation, drafts, [circa 1920-1929] (Box 6, Folder 454)
      - State and federal legislation, drafts (deteriorated), [circa 1920-1929] (Box 18, Folder 1090)
      - Domicile laws, notes and reports, [circa 1920-1929] (Box 6, Folder 455)
      - ERA legislation, notes and drafts, 1920-1935 (Box 6, Folder 456)
      - ERA legislation, notes and drafts, 1936-1967, undated (Box 6, Folder 457)
      - Notes and reports on "protective" laws, 1913-1916, undated (Box 6, Folder 458)
      - Misc. legal reports and notes, 1911-1939, undated (Box 6, Folder 459)
    - Nationality of Women
      - General, arranged chronologically, 1930-1939, undated (Box 6, Folders 460-480)
      - General, arranged chronologically (deteriorated, from folders 461-463, 469-480), 1930-1939, undated (Box 18, Folders 1091-1093)
    - Press Releases
      - General, arranged chronologically, 1917-1969, undated (Box 6, Folders 481-494)
      - General, arranged chronologically (deteriorated, from folders 481-487, 493-494), 1917-1938, undated (Box 18, Folders 1094-1095)
    - Financial reports and statements
      - Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage. Financial statements, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 495)
      - Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage. Financial statements, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 496)
      - Equal Rights, 1935-1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 497)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1922-1923 (Box 6, Folder 498)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1926-1931 (Box 6, Folder 499)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1932 Apr-Jul (Box 6, Folder 500)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1932 Sep - 1933 Jul (Box 6, Folder 501)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1931 Nov - 1933 Sep (Box 6, Folder 502)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1933 Sep-Oct (Box 6, Folder 503)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1933 Jul-Nov (Box 6, Folder 504)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1934 Apr (Box 6, Folder 505)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1934 Aug - 1934 Dec (Box 6, Folder 506)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 507)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 508)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements, 1951 Jul - 1953 Jun (Box 6, Folder 509)
      - National Woman’s Party. Financial statements (deteriorated, from folders 495-497, 501-502), 1914-1933 (Box 18, Folders 1096-1097)
      - National Woman’s Party Belmont Memorial Fund. Report, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 510)
      - National Woman’s Party General Fund, 1936 Nov (Box 6, Folder 511)
      - National Woman’s Party International Fund. Financial Reports, 1930-1933, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 512)
      - National Woman’s Party International Fund. Financial Reports and Statements (deteriorated, from folders 506, 508, and 512), 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 1098)
      - National Woman’s Party Investment and Endowment Fund Committee. Reports, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 513)
      - National Woman’s Party Investment and Endowment Fund Committee. Reports, 1936, 1953, undated (Box 6, Folder 514)
      - National Woman’s Party tentative and proposed budgets, 1942, undated (Box 6, Folder 515)
      - Expenses of Elsie M. Hill, 1917-1933, undated (Box 6, Folder 516)
      - Inter-American Commission of Women. Financial Statements, 1929-1938 (Box 6, Folder 517)
    - Pamphlets and Periodicals
      - Pamphlets, 1922-1924 (Box 7, Folder 518)
      - Pamphlets, 1926-1929 (Box 7, Folder 519)
      - Pamphlets, 1934-1960 (Box 7, Folder 520)
      - The National Woman’s Party Bulletin, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 521)
      - The National Woman’s Party Bulletin, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 522)
      - The National Woman’s Party Bulletin, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 523)
      - Equal Rights, 1932-1951 (Box 7, Folder 524)
      - Equal Rights, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 525)
      - National Woman’s Party. Pamphlets, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 526-527)
      - National Woman’s Party. Letterhead, undated (Box 7, Folder 528)
    - Ephemera
      - Miscellaneous, arranged chronologically, 1913-1949 (Box 7, Folders 526-544)
      - Miscellaneous, arranged chronologically, 1950-1970, undated (Box 7, Folders 545-558)
      - Forms and stationery, undated (Box 7, Folder 559)
      - Miscellaneous lists, 1911-1926 (Box 7, Folder 560)
      - Miscellaneous lists, 1931-1965, undated (Box 7, Folder 561)
      - Miscellaneous notes and resolutions, 1914-1961, undated (Box 7, Folder 562)
      - Miscellaneous (deteriorated), 1913-1961 (Box 18, Folders 1099-1102)
      - World Woman's Party, 1926-1953, undated (Box 7, Folder 563)
    - U.S. Government Documents
      - Alva Belmont House and tax-exempt status of the National Woman’s Party, 1925-1960 (Box 5, Folder 564)
      - Civil Rights, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 565)
      - Civil Rights, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 566)
      - Civil Rights, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 567)
      - Civil Rights, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 568)
      - Employment and wages of women, 1935-1937 (Box 5, Folder 569)
      - Equal Rights Amendment, 1929-1931 (Box 5, Folder 570)
      - Equal Rights Amendment, 1932-1938 (Box 5, Folder 571)
      - Equal Rights Amendment, 1943-1956 (Box 5, Folder 572)
      - Equal Rights Amendment (deteriorated, from folder 572), 1943-1956 (Box 17, Folder 1085)
      - Equal Rights Amendment, 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 573)
      - Equal Rights Amendment, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 574)
      - Equal Rights Amendment [contains 2 docs with AP’s annotations], 1963-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 575)
      - Nationality and immigration, [192?]-1932 (Box 5, Folder 576)
      - Nationality and immigration, 1933-1940 (Box 5, Folder 577)
      - Prostitution, 1909-1910 (Box 5, Folder 578)
      - Prostitution, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 579)
      - Prostitution, 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 580)
      - Miscellaneous, 1924-1970 (Box 5, Folder 581)
      - Children’s Bureau, 1906-1928 (Box 7, Folder 582)
      - Children’s Bureau, 1929-1938 (Box 7, Folder 583)
      - Women’s Bureau, 1926-1928 (Box 7, Folder 584)
      - Women’s Bureau, 1931-1942, undated (Box 7, Folder 585)
      - Miscellaneous state documents, 1916-1929 (Box 7, Folder 586)
      - Miscellaneous state documents, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 587)
      - Miscellaneous state documents, 1959-1968 (Box 7, Folder 588)
      - Miscellaneous state documents (deteriorated, from folders 582-589), undated (Box 18, Folder 1103)
    - Other U.S. Women's Associations
      - Pamphlets, 1905-1918 (Box 8, Folder 589)
      - Pamphlets, 1921-1928 (Box 8, Folder 590)
      - Pamphlets, 1930-1950 (Box 8, Folder 591)
      - Pamphlets, 1965-1968 (Box 8, Folder 592)
    - Periodicals
      - Connecticut League of Woman Voters. The Woman Voter’s Bulletin, 1929-1932 (Box 8, Folder 593)
      - Lucy Stone League Bulletin, circa 1920-1970 (Box 8, Folder 594)
      - Women’s Legislative Council of Washington. Legislative Counsellor, 1919-1921 (Box 8, Folder 595)
      - Women’s Legislative Council of Washington. Legislative Counsellor (deteriorated), 1919-1921 (Box 18, Folder 1104)
      - Ephemera, 1910-1970, undated (Box 8, Folders 596-604)
      - Ephemera (deteriorated), 1910-1970, undated (Box 18, Folder 1105)
    - International Women's Associations
      - Pamphlets and serial publications, 1919-1926 (Box 8, Folder 605)
      - Pamphlets and serial publications, 1929-1937 (Box 8, Folder 606)
      - Pamphlets and serial publications, 1938-1963 (Box 8, Folder 607)
      - Ephemera, 1909-1930 (Box 8, Folder 608)
      - Ephemera, 1931-1937 (Box 8, Folder 609)
      - Ephemera, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 610)
      - Ephemera (deteriorated, from folders 607-610), 1909-1938 (Box 18, Folder 1106)
      - Ephemera, 1941-1963, undated (Box 8, Folder 611)
    - United Nations
      - Notes of Elsie Hill, 1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 612)
      - Notes of Alice Paul re: Human Rights Covenant, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 613)
      - Human Rights publications, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 614)
      - Human Rights publications, 1952-1961 (Box 8, Folders 615-617)
      - Status of women publications, 1951-1967 (Box 8, Folders 618-623)
      - Journal of the General Assembly, 1950-1961 (Box 10, Folders 624-625)
      - Miscellaneous publications, 1950-1960, undated (Box 10, Folder 626)
      - U.N. Charter (English, French, Spanish), undated (Box 10, Folder 627)
      - Committee and organization membership lists, 1953-1961 (Box 10, Folder 628)
      - Delegations, 1950-1961 (Box 10, Folder 629)
      - Permanent missions and delegations, 1952-1959 (Box 10, Folder 630)
      - Elsie Hill’s press tickets and passes, undated (Box 10, Folder 631)
      - League of Nations miscellaneous publications, 1931-1935 (Box 10, Folder 632)
    - Miscellaneous social and political activism
      - Anti-war ephemera, 1916-1919, undated (Box 8, Folder 633)
      - Anti-war ephemera, 1931-1937 (Box 8, Folder 634)
      - Anti-war ephemera, 1949-1968, undated (Box 8, Folder 635)
      - Anti-war ephemera, 1949-1968, undated (Box 8, Folder 636)
      - Civil liberties and human rights ephemera, 1950-1966, undated (Box 8, Folder 637)
      - Labor ephemera, 1919-1937 (Box 8, Folder 638)
      - Miscellaneous social activism ephemera, 1909-1967, undated (Box 8, Folders 639-640)
      - The Arbitrator, 1931-1935 (Box 9, Folder 641)
      - Political ephemera, 1909-1953 (Box 9, Folder 642)
      - Political ephemera, 1960-1967, undated (Box 9, Folder 643)
      - Miscellaneous ephemera (deteriorated, from folders 633-642), 1909-1967, undated (Box 18, Folders 1107-1108)
    - Social and political activism in Connecticut
      - Hill political campaign material, 1932-1950, undated (Box 9, Folder 644)
      - Hill political campaign material (deteriorated), 1932-1950, undated (Box 18, Folder 1109)
      - Fairfield County (CT) Republican Women’s Association Annual Report, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 645)
      - Disposal of Gilbert Farm, Redding, undated (Box 9, Folder 646)
      - Connecticut educational legislation, 1925-1961 (Box 9, Folder 647)
      - Miscellaneous Norwalk material, undated (Box 9, Folder 648)
      - Norwalk Common Council Meeting minutes, 1961-1966 (Box 9, Folder 649)
      - Norwalk N.A.A.C.P., 1964-1966 (Box 9, Folder 650)
      - Connecticut politics, 1932-1968, undated (Box 9, Folder 651)
      - Redding Bicentennial, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 652)
      - Connecticut state forests and parks, 1925-1965, undated (Box 9, Folder 653)
      - Connecticut state forests and parks [pamphlets and map], 1926-1940 (Box 9, Folder 654)